It's very simple to write a subtitle
You just have to specify the time when you want the text to be displayed
You can use italic and bold!
Make sure you display the sentence long enough to be read :)
To start choose a section below and replace the lorem ipsum with your name
Unjust laws exist;
shall we be content to obey them,
or shall we endeavor to amend them,
and obey them until we have succeeded,
or shall we transgress them at once?
Henry David Thoreau
The co-founder of the social news and entertainment website "reddit" has been found dead
He surely was a prodigy althought he never [?] thought of himself like that
He was totally unexcited about studing businesses and making money
There's a profound sense of loss tonight in Highland Park Aaron Swartz's hometown
as loved ones say goodbye to one of the Internet's brightest lights
...Open Access and computer activits are mourning his loss
...an astonishing intellect. You talk to people who knew him
...he was killed by the government and MIT betrayed all of its basic principles
...they wanted to make an example out of it, ok?
Governments have sensational[?] desire to confront
...he was potentially facing 35 years in prison and 1 million dollars fine
Raising questions of prosecutorial zeal and I would say even miscondut.
Have you looked into that particular matter and reached any conclusions?
Growing up, you know, I slowly had this process of realising that
all the things around me, that people had told me
were just the natural way things were, the way things always would be.
They weren't natural at all. They were things that could be changed
and they were thing that more importantly were wrong and should change.
And once I realised that, there was really kind of no going back
The Internet's Own Boy
Welcome to story reading time
The name of the book is 'Paddington at the fair'
Well, he was born in Highland Park and grew up here
Aaron came from a family of three brothers all extraordinarly bright
The box is flipping over!
So, we were all, you know, not the best behaved children
you know, three boys running around all the time, causing trouble
Mom: No, no, no... Aaron!?
Aaron: What?
But, I've come to the realization: Aaron learned how to learn at a very young age
Toc, toc!?
Who's here?
Aaron!
Aaron who?
Aaron funny man
He knew what he wanted, he always wanted to do it.
He always accomplished what he wanted.
His curiosity was endless
Here's the little picture of a [?] [?]
One day he said to Susan: "Let's do three family entertainment[?] downtown in the park"
Three family entertainment[?] downtown in the park
He was three at the time
She said: "What are you talking about?"
He said: "Look it says here on on the refrigerator"
"Three family entertainment[?] downtown in the park"
She was flurred and astonished that he could read
It's called: "My family seder"
The seder night is different from all other nights
I remember once we were are the University of Chicago library
I pulled a book off the shelf that was like from 1900
and showed to him, [?]you know this is an extraordinary place
We all were curious children but Aaron really liked learning and really liked teaching
Today we're going to read the ABC backwards z, y, x, w, ...
I remember he came home from his first algebra class
he was like: "Noah, let me teach you algebra!"
and I'm like: "What is algebra?"
and he was always like that
Now I press button, click button
there, now he's got that[?], now it's a pink
When he was at 2 or 3 three years old an Bob introduced him to computers
then he just took off like crazy on them
[?]
We all had computers, but Aaron really talked to them, really talked to the Internet
Looking at the computer?
No, how [?]
He started programming from a really young age.
I remember the first program that I wrote with him was in basic
and  was a Star Wars trivia game
He sat down with me in the basement were the computer was
for hours programming this game
The problem that I kept having with him was that
there was nothing that I woudn't done
and to him there'sat always something to do
always something that programming could solve
The way that Aaron always thought is that programming is magic
you can accomplish this things that normal humans can't
Aaron made an ATM using like a Macintosh and like a cardboard box
One year for Halloween I didn't know what I wanted to be
and he thought would be really really cool if I dressed up
like his new favourite computer which at the time was the original iMac
and he hated dressing up for Hallowen but he loved convincing other people to dress like other things he wanted to see
[?]
Guys, come on, look at the camera
He made this website called "The Info" where people could just fill in information
Like, I'm sure someone out there knows all about gold, gold leafing[?].
Why aren't they writing about that on this website?
And then other people can come at a later point and read that information
and edit the information if they thought that it was bad
Not too dissimilar from WikiPedia, all right?
This is before WikiPedia begun
and this is developed by a 12 year old
in his room, by himself
running on this tiny server using ancient technology
One of the teacher's response like:
"This is a terrible idea, you can't just let anyone author the dictionary, like author the encyclopedia"
"For a whole reason we have scholars to write these book for us"
"How did you ever had such a terrible idea"
Me and my other brother would be like: "Yeah, you know"
"WikiPedia is cool but we had that in our house, like 5 years ago"
Aaron's website "The Info.org" wins a school competition hosted by the Cambridge based web design firm ArsDigita
We all went to Cambridge when he won the ArsDigita Prize
and, you know, we had no clue of what Aaron was doing
it was obvious that the pirze was really important
Aaron soon became involved with on-line programming communities
than in the process of shaping a new tool for web
He concept is like[?]: "Ben, there's a really awesome thing that I'm working on"
"you need to hear about it"
I'm like: "Yeah, what is it?"
He says: "Is this thing called RSS"
And he explains me what RSS is
and I like: "Why is that useful? Aaron, is a site using it? Why would I want to use it?"
There was this mailing list for people who were working on RSS and XML more generally
and there was a person on it named Aaron Swartz
who was combatitive but very smart and who had lots of good ideas
and he did never come to the face to face meetings
and they said: "You know, when are you gonna come to one of those face to face meetings?"
He said: "You know, I don't think my mom would let me, you know I just turned 14"
So the first reaction was, well you know, this person this colleague we've been working with all year
was 13 years old when we were working with him and is only 14 now
and their second reaction was: "Christ, we really want to meet him!"
"You know that's extraordinary"
Was part of the community that drafted RSS
What he was doing was to help building the plumbing for modern hypertext
and the piece he was working on, RSS, was a tool that you can use to get summaries
of things that are going on on other web pages
Commonly you would use this for a blog
You might have 10 or 20 people's blog you wanna read
you use the RSS feeds, these summaries of what's going on on those other pages
to create a unified list of all the stuff that's going on
Aaron was really young but he understood the technology
and he saw that was imperfect and looked for ways to help make it better
So his mom bundles[?] him on a plane in Chicago, we pick him up in San Francisco
we introduced him to interesting people to argue with
and we marvelled at his horrific eating habits
he only eat white food, only like, you know, steamed rice
and not white rice, beacause that was not sufficiently white, and white bread, and so on
and you kind of marvel at the quality of the debate emerging from what appeared to be a small boy's mouth
and you think, this is a kid, is really going to go somewhere if he doesn't die of scroovy[?]
Aaron you're up
I think the difference is that now you can't make companies like that per-se
you can't have companies that just like "let's sell dog food over the Internet, dog food over the cellphones"
but there still lot of innovation going on, I think, if you don't see the innovation maybe your head is in the sand
He takes on this alpha-male personality where he's sort of like
"I'm smarter than you, and because I'm smarter than you I'm better than you, and I can tell you what to do"
It's an extension of him being like a kind of torpe[?]
So you aggregate all these computers together and now they're solving big problems
like searching for aliens or trying to cure cancer
First I met him on IRC, on Internet Relay Chat, he didn't just write code
he also got people excited about solving problems, he was a connector
the free culture movement, which[?] had lot of his energy
I think Aaron was trying to make the world work.
He was trying to fix it
He had a very kind of strong personality, that definetly ruffled[?] feathers at times
and wasn't necessarily the case that he was always confortable in the world
and the world wasn't confortable with him
Aaron got into high school, and was really just sick of school
he didn't like it, he didn't like any of the classes he had been taught
he didn't like the teachers
Aaron really knew how to get information
He was like, I don't need to go to these teachers to know how to do geometry
I can just read the geometry book
and I don't need to go to the teacher to learn their version of American history
I have like three historical compilations here like I can just read them
and I'm not interested in that, I'm interested in the Web
I was very frustrated with school
I thought, you know, the teachers didn't know what they were talking about
[position]
they were very domineering and controlling, homework was kind of a sham[?]
I was just like, you know, all the way are penstick[?] together and force them to do busy work
and, you know, I started reading books about the history of education and how this educational system was developed
and, you know, alternative ways to do it[?] people could actually learn things
instead of just regurgitating facts that the teachers told them
and that kind of led me down this path of questioning things
and once I questioned the school I was in, I questioned the society that built the school
I questioned the businesses that the schools were training people for
I questioned the government that, you know, setup this whole structure
One of the themes he was more passionate about was copyright, especially in those early days
Copyright has always been something overburden on publishing industry and on readers
but it wasn't an excessive burden
it was a reasonable institution to have in place
to make sure that people got paid
What Aaron generation experienced was the collision
between this antique copyright system
and this amazing new thing we were trying to build, the Internet and the Web
These things collided and what we got was chaos
He then met Harward law professot Lawrence Lessig
who was then challenging copyright law in the supreme court
A young Aaron Swartz flew to Washington to listen to the supreme court hearings
I'm Aaron Swartz and I'm here to listen to the Eldred ...to see the Eldred argument
Why did you fly out here from Chicago and come all this way to see the Eldred argument?
That's a more difficult question
I don't know, I'm very excited to see the supreme court
especially in such a prestigious case as this one
Lessig was also moving forward with a new way to define copyright on the Internet
it was called Creative Commons
So the simple idea of Creative Commons is to give people, creators
a simple way to mark their creativity
with the freedoms they intended to carry
So copyright is about "all rights reserved"
then this is a kind of "some rights reserved" bottle[?]
It's I want a simple way to say to you "here's what you can do with my work"
even if there are other things which you need to get my permission before you could do
And Aaron's role was the computer part
like how do you architect the licenses
so that would be simple and understandable and expressed in way that machines could process it
And people are like, why do you have this fifteen year old kid
writing the specifications of creative commons?
like, don't you think that's a huge mistake?
and larry is like: "the biggest mistake that we would have is not listening to this kid"
embarrassing[?] is not even tall enough to get over the podium
and it wasn't one of those movable podiums
so this embarrassing thing that once he put his screen up nobody could see his face
When we come to our website here
and we've got few licences
it gives you this list of options explaining what it means
and we thought three set of questions
Do you want to require attribution?
Do you want to allow commercial uses of your work?
Do you want to allow modifications of your work?
I was floored
just completely fiberglassed that these adults regarded him as an adult
Aaron stood up there in front an whole audience full of people
and just started talking about the platform that he created for Creative Commons
And they where all listening to him, just
I was sitting AT the back thinking:
"he's just a kid, why're listening to him?"
but they did
well I don't think I comprehended it fully
Though critics have said that it does little to ensure artists get payed for their work
the success of Creative Commons has been enourmous
Currently on the website flickr alone over 200 million people use some form of Creative Commons license
He contributed through his technical abilities
and yet it was not simply a technical matter to him
Aaron Often wrote candidly in his personal blog
I think deeply about things and I want others to do likewise.
I work for ideas and learn from people. I don’t like excluding people.
I’m a perfectionist, but I won’t let that get in the way of publication.
Except for education and entertainment, I’m not going to waste my time on things that won’t have impact.
I try to be friends with everyone, but I hate it when you don’t take me seriously.
I don’t hold grudges (it’s not productive) but I learn from my experience.
I want to make the world a better place.
In 2004 Swartz leaves Highland Park and enrolls in Stanford University
He had also diverticolite[?] which was very troubling
and we were concerned about him taking his medications.
He got hospitalized and he would take this cocktail pills everyday
and one of these pills was a steroid which dauted his growth and
made him feel different from any of the other students
lorem ipsum